<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>conference on Alexandra&#39;s Log</title>
    <link>/tags/conference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in conference on Alexandra&#39;s Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 18:06:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Career opportunities and YouTube videos</title>
      <link>/posts/career-opportunities-and-youtube-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 18:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/career-opportunities-and-youtube-videos/</guid>
      <description>Hum&amp;hellip; I guess it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last blogged. This time however I have something to show off: Till&amp;rsquo;s and my presentation at CampKDE is on YouTube. And without further ado &amp;ndash; enjoy the show. The slides are quite visible in the video but I thought embedding them here wouldn&amp;rsquo;t hurt.
View more presentations from Alexandra Leisse.
If you are interested in the rest of the talks, head over to the KDE Promo channel on YouTube and take a look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organize a Booth and Keep Your Sanity</title>
      <link>/posts/organize-a-booth-and-keep-your-sanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 15:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/organize-a-booth-and-keep-your-sanity/</guid>
      <description>After having a quick chat with Kévin Ottens on IRC we agreed that it would be useful to write up a small how-to explaining the Art of Booth Organization™ as a follow up on the how-to for sprints I posted earlier. He has been poking me about it repeatedly, so voilà, Monsieur, finalement, c&amp;rsquo;est fait. While writing down all those steps I realized that organizing a booth is more complex than I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home At Last</title>
      <link>/posts/home-at-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 11:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/home-at-last/</guid>
      <description>Three weeks of travel are finally over. I enjoyed most of it but it took it&amp;rsquo;s toll. One of the reasons I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel the summit was as successful for me personally than it could have been. During the four days in Berlin I spent mostly in the halls of LinuxTag, I had the energy and ease to walk around and talk to people although the preparation of the whole event had taken quite some effort from my side.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>