<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rants on Alexandra&#39;s Log</title>
    <link>/tags/rants/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rants on Alexandra&#39;s Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 20:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Community: my first steps</title>
      <link>/posts/community-first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 20:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/community-first-steps/</guid>
      <description>Time flies. 15 years ago I published my first community fuelled website. It&amp;rsquo;s long gone of course but I can still tell the story. It all started with an anniversary One of my all-time favourite children&amp;rsquo;s TV show went into it&amp;rsquo;s 25th year at the time. I still watched it on a regular basis and so I had an idea. Why not send a special greeting card? One that would be fun to make and a bit different?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You know you travel too much if ...</title>
      <link>/posts/you-know-you-travel-too-much-if/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 22:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/you-know-you-travel-too-much-if/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;240&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;quot;Image via Wikipedia&amp;rdquo;][/caption]
&amp;hellip; the driver recognizes you when you get onto the bus to your local airport. &amp;hellip; you don&amp;rsquo;t even look up the number of the check-in counter anymore. &amp;hellip; you have all your make-up in a little bag you don&amp;rsquo;t even unpack anymore. &amp;hellip; you have various cosmetic products that are labeled in foreign languages. &amp;hellip; you find yourself postponing the visit to the duty free shop because you will visit a bigger or better one soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train-Networking</title>
      <link>/posts/train-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 18:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/train-networking/</guid>
      <description>oder: Warum ich gerne Zug fahre Alle Welt hasst Zugfahren. Ich nicht. Ich lerne nämlich einen Haufen interessanter Leute beim Zugfahren kennen. Nun mag es helfen, weiblich und ahnsehnlich zu sein. Geschäftsreisende Männer unterhalten sich jedenfalls gerne mit mir, während sie im Zug nichts zu tun haben. Denn mal ehrlich: wer hat schon nach einem langen Tag noch Lust, ausgerechnet im Zug irgendetwas zu arbeiten, wenn man sich stattdessen nett unterhalten kann.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frohe Weihnachten</title>
      <link>/posts/frohe-weihnachten/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2007 12:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/frohe-weihnachten/</guid>
      <description>Ich wünsche Euch allen ruhige und besinnliche Weihnachtstage und ein gutes und erfolgreiches Neues Jahr. Hoffentlich ein Jahr mit vielen Blogeinträgen &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>