<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travel on Alexandra&#39;s Log</title>
    <link>/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in travel on Alexandra&#39;s Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 11:05:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Home At Last</title>
      <link>/posts/home-at-last/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 11:05:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/home-at-last/</guid>
      <description>Three weeks of travel are finally over. I enjoyed most of it but it took it&amp;rsquo;s toll. One of the reasons I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel the summit was as successful for me personally than it could have been. During the four days in Berlin I spent mostly in the halls of LinuxTag, I had the energy and ease to walk around and talk to people although the preparation of the whole event had taken quite some effort from my side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You know you travel too much if ...</title>
      <link>/posts/you-know-you-travel-too-much-if/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 22:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/you-know-you-travel-too-much-if/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;240&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;quot;Image via Wikipedia&amp;rdquo;][/caption]
&amp;hellip; the driver recognizes you when you get onto the bus to your local airport. &amp;hellip; you don&amp;rsquo;t even look up the number of the check-in counter anymore. &amp;hellip; you have all your make-up in a little bag you don&amp;rsquo;t even unpack anymore. &amp;hellip; you have various cosmetic products that are labeled in foreign languages. &amp;hellip; you find yourself postponing the visit to the duty free shop because you will visit a bigger or better one soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On The Road Again</title>
      <link>/posts/on-the-road-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 21:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/on-the-road-again/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the German Bahn, I gained an hour offline in a train. All my tasks I could finish without the internet are done now, so I thought to myself I could as well blog something. I squeezed myself into the ICE to Basel SBB with a incredibly heavy suitcase, a backpack, a cardboard roll holding posters and my handbag. A whole hour later than planned because of severe stupidness on my side.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>