<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>socialmedia on Alexandra&#39;s Log</title>
    <link>/tags/socialmedia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in socialmedia on Alexandra&#39;s Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 20:27:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/socialmedia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Software Product Releases with Social Media Tools</title>
      <link>/posts/supporting-releases-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 20:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/supporting-releases-social-media/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been sitting on this mind map for quite some time now but never got around to properly documenting my thoughts. Chances are that it will never happen so I&amp;rsquo;ll put it up for grabs. The mind map is huge. In an ideal world, a new release would be supported by a whole team pushing buttons on all sorts of social networks. The world is unfortunately rarely ideal, so the team will have to prioritize depending on its size, audience and preference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KDE has Super Cow Powers Too</title>
      <link>/posts/kde-has-super-cow-powers-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2009 21:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/kde-has-super-cow-powers-too/</guid>
      <description>Ariya complained about me being too theoretical again and wanted examples for my last blog. So here we go. One of my alltime favourite online companies is moo.com. I bet you heard me talking about it already. They make those lovely mini cards, post cards, shiny little stickers, and cleverly use a lot of 3rd party services on the web both for their products and their marketing. Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Social</title>
      <link>/posts/being-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2009 11:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/being-social/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;240&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;quot;Social Network by Luc Legay&amp;rdquo;][/caption] I have been thinking. This is not quite unusual but this time it had a reason: Augustín&amp;rsquo;s blog about Social Networks and Lydia&amp;rsquo;s identi.ca review. With the introduction of so called Social Networks and Social Features on a lot of websites, the way we see and use the internet has changed from broadcasting to joining conversations. The good news is that KDE - like most FLOSS communities - is very well set.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>