<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CampKDE on Alexandra&#39;s Log</title>
    <link>/tags/campkde/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CampKDE on Alexandra&#39;s Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 18:06:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/campkde/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Career opportunities and YouTube videos</title>
      <link>/posts/career-opportunities-and-youtube-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 18:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/career-opportunities-and-youtube-videos/</guid>
      <description>Hum&amp;hellip; I guess it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last blogged. This time however I have something to show off: Till&amp;rsquo;s and my presentation at CampKDE is on YouTube. And without further ado &amp;ndash; enjoy the show. The slides are quite visible in the video but I thought embedding them here wouldn&amp;rsquo;t hurt.
View more presentations from Alexandra Leisse.
If you are interested in the rest of the talks, head over to the KDE Promo channel on YouTube and take a look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell Jamaica</title>
      <link>/posts/farewell-jamaica/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2009 10:46:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/farewell-jamaica/</guid>
      <description>I have finally recovered from the trip to Jamaica. It took me the whole weekend, though. Maybe staying up late didn&amp;rsquo;t really help&amp;hellip; Or I&amp;rsquo;m just getting old. CampKDE was a cozy but great meeting and I really enjoyed spending time with people I already knew rather well and those I hadn&amp;rsquo;t met before. Although distractions were many, I got to all the topics I had on my list and learnt a lot from Mauricio and - I must admit - Wade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CampKDE Day 3</title>
      <link>/posts/campkde-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 19:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/campkde-day-3/</guid>
      <description>Both days of conference are over by now. The talks were quite technical, but still interesting to me. At least the part that I actually understood. Nevertheless I learnt something: I knew about cultural differences between Asia and Europe before but it was new to me that those between Europe and (South- and Middle-) America were nearly as big. For today I plan a BoF on collaboration between the KDE community in North America and Qt Software to plan how to leverage KDE along with Qt and hopefully another one on the needs of the communities on Middle and Southern America, now that I actually have members of our community from there at hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Camping</title>
      <link>/posts/going-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2009 19:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/going-camping/</guid>
      <description>When the alarm woke me up at 5 yesterday morning, I found it hard to believe that I would be spending most of the day on various planes and crossing several timezones. To be honest, it felt close to impossible to get out of bed. But I convinced myself at last and crawled down the ladder of my loft bed. At 7.55 and -6° C Thomas and me got onto the plane to Heathrow.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>