<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>event on Alexandra&#39;s Log</title>
    <link>/tags/event/</link>
    <description>Recent content in event on Alexandra&#39;s Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 18:06:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Career opportunities and YouTube videos</title>
      <link>/posts/career-opportunities-and-youtube-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 18:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/career-opportunities-and-youtube-videos/</guid>
      <description>Hum&amp;hellip; I guess it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last blogged. This time however I have something to show off: Till&amp;rsquo;s and my presentation at CampKDE is on YouTube. And without further ado &amp;ndash; enjoy the show. The slides are quite visible in the video but I thought embedding them here wouldn&amp;rsquo;t hurt.
View more presentations from Alexandra Leisse.
If you are interested in the rest of the talks, head over to the KDE Promo channel on YouTube and take a look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organize a Booth and Keep Your Sanity</title>
      <link>/posts/organize-a-booth-and-keep-your-sanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 15:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/organize-a-booth-and-keep-your-sanity/</guid>
      <description>After having a quick chat with Kévin Ottens on IRC we agreed that it would be useful to write up a small how-to explaining the Art of Booth Organization™ as a follow up on the how-to for sprints I posted earlier. He has been poking me about it repeatedly, so voilà, Monsieur, finalement, c&amp;rsquo;est fait. While writing down all those steps I realized that organizing a booth is more complex than I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Help</title>
      <link>/posts/call-for-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 20:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/call-for-help/</guid>
      <description>Image via Wikipedia
1.5 years ago, Franz was in the same position as I am now: he needed a helping hand. And unfortunately it&amp;rsquo;s the same event again. There is an OpenExpo in Winterthur coming up on 23rd and 24th September and so far noone has stepped up to organize it. These expos are nice events (incl. catering) and stunningly well organized by /ch/open - there is really not much to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KDE release event in Zurich</title>
      <link>/posts/kde-release-event-in-zurich/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2009 14:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/kde-release-event-in-zurich/</guid>
      <description>I attended the 4.2 release event in Zurich on Wednesday and I must say: it was pretty crowded. Pascal and Luca and whoelse helped them did a good job on organizing the whole event, including Apéro with FreeBeer and snacks. I listened to the keynote by Georg Greve, President of the FSFE, and to Aaron who impressed with his live presentation. I found a first set of photos on flickr. It gives a nice idea of the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KOffice 2 talk</title>
      <link>/posts/koffice-2-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2008 20:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/koffice-2-talk/</guid>
      <description>I made my debut as a speaker on wednesday. I think I mentioned that before&amp;hellip; once or twice&amp;hellip; maybe&amp;hellip; Just let me put it like that: it was exciting and I liked it. And I&amp;rsquo;m so happy how my slides turned out that I will put them up again here. Call me vain. [UPDATE] I heard your complaints. Let me know if this slideshare widget doesn&amp;rsquo;t work either.
KOffice 2 overview</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenExpo</title>
      <link>/posts/openexpo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2008 07:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/openexpo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back to lovely Switzerland.
Claudia and I arrived yesterday around tea time after missing our connection at Zurich. Travelling by German Bahn always is an adventurous thing&amp;hellip; especially when I travel to Switzerland.
During our slightly longer than planned trip I added the final polish to my talk which is scheduled for this early afternoon and wrote my thoughts on a *huge* staple of notecards. I was even asked if I did my homework on the train!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Akademy 2008</title>
      <link>/posts/akademy-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2008 11:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/akademy-2008/</guid>
      <description>I went to my first Akademy this year. And I get the strong feeling that I should have kept my mouth shut a lot of work is ahead of me. As you might have noticed there is a promo team. And we do work, too. We came up with some nice and hopefully helpful ideas during our BoFs. There will be a complete new system to help everybody on organizing events which is already under development and we agreed on using common web2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Need You!</title>
      <link>/posts/i-need-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2008 13:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/i-need-you/</guid>
      <description>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s not me alone actually. But it made a good headline. ;) I registered a booth at the OpenExpo in Winterthur and would be glad about any helping hand there. Luca Gugelmann and Roland Wolters gave me a vague &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo; but both couldn&amp;rsquo;t really promise anything yet. To help me out you don&amp;rsquo;t have to be super-expert or developer, being able to talk about and show some KDE4 goodness will be absolutely fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinuxTag 2008</title>
      <link>/posts/linuxtag-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 19:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/linuxtag-2008/</guid>
      <description>After trying to visit LinuxTag already last year (and failing unfortunately) I made it to Berlin this time. In beforehand some organizing was still needed as Franz Keferböck who initially planned to take care of this couldn&amp;rsquo;t handle it because he temporarily had no internet access. So I jumped in and together with Claudia Rauch - the smart and lovely KDE office girl - we got it going for the booth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>